- HERE WE GO.
开始了。
UP, UP, UP.
往上，往上，往上。
AH! WE'RE AT THE TOP OF THE LOG RIDE. AH!
啊！我们到了木筏滑道的顶端。啊！
WE CAN SEE THE WHOLE WATER PARK.
我们可以看到整个水上乐园。
AND DOWN WE GO.
然后我们下去了。
all: AHH!
大家：啊！
- SHARP RIGHT TURN. all: AHH!
急右转。大家：啊！
- HARD BANK LEFT.
猛左倾。
all: AHH!
大家：啊！
- HERE COMES THE CAMERAS! EYES OPEN!
摄像机来了！眼睛睁开！
- HOW DID WE DO?
我们做得怎么样？
- HOW'D WE DO? HOW'D WE DO?
我们做得怎么样？我们做得怎么样？
WE HAVE EIGHT EYES, AND SEVEN OF THEM ARE CLOSED.
我们有八只眼睛，其中七只都闭着。
WELL, COME ON. LET'S PRACTICE AGAIN.
好了，来吧。我们再练习一次。
WE'RE FINALLY TALL ENOUGH TO RIDE THE RED BOMBER LOG FLUME,
我们终于长到可以乘坐红轰炸机木筏的高度了，
AND WE NEED A GREAT PICTURE TO PROVE IT.
我们需要一张好照片来证明这一点。
- I WASN'T SCARED.
我并不害怕。
- NOBODY SAID YOU WERE SCARED.
没人说你害怕。
- YOU'RE THE ONE WHO LOOKS SCARED.
你看起来才像是害怕的那个。
YOU'RE WHITE AS A GHOST.
你的脸色苍白得像鬼一样。
- I JUST NEED A TAN. I'M NOT SCARED.
- 我只是需要晒黑一点。我没在害怕。
- STOP SAYING I'M SCARED. I AM NOT SCARED.
- 别再说我害怕了。我不害怕。
- IS MY HAIR THINNING?
- 我的头发是不是变稀疏了？
NOW I'M SCARED.
现在我有点害怕了。
I DON'T WANT TO END UP LOOKING LIKE--OH, HEY DAD.
我不想最后看起来像——哦，嘿，爸爸。
- OH, SMELLS LIKE A WHALE'S BLOWHOLE.
- 哦，闻起来像鲸鱼的喷气孔。
DID YOU BRUSH YOUR TEETH TODAY?
你今天刷牙了吗？
HAVE ANY OF YOU BRUSHED YOUR TEETH TODAY?
你们有人今天刷过牙吗？
ALL RIGHT, MOUTH CHECK.
好吧，检查一下口腔。
LET'S GO.
我们走吧。
OH.
哦。
OH, WHY DID I ASK FOR THAT?
哦，我为什么要问那个？
I AM SO TIRED OF HAVING TO TELL YOU KIDS
我真是厌倦了每天都要告诉你们这些孩子
TO BRUSH YOUR TEETH EVERY DAY.
每天刷牙。
- THEN TAKE A DAY OFF, MY MAN.
那就休息一天吧，伙计。
YOU DESERVE IT.
你值得的。
- AND IT'S NOT JUST YOUR TEETH.
而且不仅仅是你们的牙齿。
EVERY DAY YOUR MOM AND I HAVE TO REMIND YOU TO MAKE YOUR BEDS,
每天你们的妈妈和我都要提醒你们整理床铺，
AND FLUSH THE TOILET,
冲马桶，
AND PICK UP YOUR SOCCER BALL.
还有捡起你们的足球。
PICK UP YOUR BOOKS,
收拾你的书本，
PICK UP YOUR SHOES, OR PUT YOUR DIRTY DISHES IN THE SINK.
捡起你的鞋子，或者把你的脏盘子放进水槽。
- WE ALWAYS REMEMBER TO DO THOSE THINGS.
- 我们总是记得做这些事情。
- GOOD MORNING EVERY--AHH!
- 大家早上好——啊！
DICKY!
迪基！
YOU LEFT YOUR SHOES ON THE STAIRS!
你把鞋子留在楼梯上了！
OW! RICKY, YOUR BOOK!
哎哟！瑞奇，你的书！
DAWN!
道恩！
all: IT WASN'T ME!
大家：不是我！
- REALLY?
- 真的吗？
THIS ISN'T YOUR SPECIAL NICKY SPOON?
- WELL, WE USED TO BE CLOSE,
BUT I WOULDN'T CALL HER SPECIAL.
- SEE, THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS WHEN YOU DON'T DO
WHAT WE TELL YOU TO DO.
- YEAH, AND WHAT'S MORE FRUSTRATING THAN ALL THIS,
IS THAT YOU KIDS NEVER TAKE RESPONSIBILITY FOR ALL THIS.
- YEAH, THERE'S TOO MUCH "IT WASN'T ME,"
GOING ON AROUND HERE,
AND THAT STOPS RIGHT NOW.
- IF THE FOUR OF YOU DON'T SHAPE UP,
如果你们四个不改正，
WE'RE NOT GOING TO THE WATER PARK THIS WEEKEND.
我们这周末就不去水上乐园了。
all: NO!
不要！
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
- [whistling melody]
[rhythmic clapping] - ♪ ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR! ♪
♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
- [whistling melody]
♪ ♪
- ♪ NA, NA, NA, NA, NA-NA ♪
♪ NA, NA, NA, NA, NA-NA ♪
- ♪ ONE, TWO ♪ - ♪ NA, NA, NA ♪
- ♪ ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR! ♪
- [whistling]
AHH!
啊！
WHAT'RE YOU DOING?
你在干什么？
- I'M JUST PUTTING MY DISHES
- 我只是把我的盘子
IN THE SINK LIKE THE RESPONSIBLE GUY I AM.
放进水槽，像我这样负责任的人。
- THANKS, BUDDY. WOW!
- 谢谢，伙计。哇！
AHH!
啊！
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
你在干什么？
- LOOKS LIKE I LEFT MY SHOES ON THE FLOOR AGAIN.
- 看来我又把鞋子落在地板上了。
SILLY ME.
我真是糊涂。
I'LL JUST PUT THEM AWAY LIKE THE RESPONSIBLE GUY I AM.
我会把它们收好，像我这样负责任的人。
- THAT I WHAT I LIKE TO HEAR.
- 我就喜欢听你这么说。
IT'S NICE TO SEE YOU GUYS TAKING SOME RESPONSIBILITY.
看到你们承担责任真是太好了。
I DEFINITELY SEE A WATER PARK IN YOUR FUTURE.
我绝对能看到你们未来会去水上乐园。
NOW IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME, IT'S SMOOTHIE TIME.
现在请原谅我，是时候喝 smoothie 了。
- OH, THAT LOOKS GOOD. CAN I HAVE SOME?
- 哦，看起来不错。我可以来点吗？
- OH NO, NO, NO, NO. SORRY PAL.
哦不，不，不，不。抱歉，伙计。
THIS SMOOTHIE IS OFF-LIMITS. IT'S AN ALL-NATURAL RECIPE TO PROMOTE HAIR GROWTH.
这个 smoothie 是禁止的。这是一个全天然的配方，旨在促进头发生长。
YOU MAY NOT HAVE NOTICED, BUT I'M A LITTLE THIN UP TOP.
你可能没注意到，我头顶有点稀疏。
- NOPE. - I DON'T SEE IT.
没有。
- OH! YOU GUYS SURE YOU CAN HANDLE ALL THAT?
我没看出来。
- NO PROBLEM. - WE'RE GOOD.
哦！你们确定能应付得了所有这些吗？
- THANKS, KIDS.
没问题。
- ALWAYS HAPPY TO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY, MOM.
我们没问题。
LIKE THE RESPONSIBLE KIDS WE ARE.
谢谢，孩子们。
- WE SHOULD GO TO THE WATER PARK EVERY WEEKEND. - I KNOW.
总是乐于承担责任，妈妈。就像我们这些负责任的孩子一样。我们应该每个周末都去水上公园。我知道。
KIDS ARE SO EASILY EXCITED BY THE SILLIEST THINGS.
孩子们对最无聊的东西都那么容易兴奋。
OOH! NEON PISTACHI-GLO ICE CREAM!
哦！霓虹开心果冰淇淋！
[gasps] all: OOH.
（吸气声）大家：哦。
- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO. HEY, HEY, HEY.
不，不，不，不，不。嘿，嘿，嘿。
EVERY TIME I BUY THIS ICE CREAM,
每次我买这种冰淇淋，
YOU GUYS SUCK IT DOWN BEFORE I CAN EVEN GET A BITE.
你们都在我还没尝到一口之前就把它吸光了。
UNTIL THIS CARTON IS EMPTY,
直到这个盒子空了，
ALL OF YOU PRETEND YOU'RE LACTOSE INTOLERANT, LIKE DICKY.
你们所有人都假装你们乳糖不耐受，像迪基那样。
- I'M WHAT?
我是什么？
AHH!
啊！
IT ALL MAKES SENSE NOW.
现在一切都解释得通了。
- SHE DID IT! - HE DID IT!
她做到了！
both: I MEAN, WE DID IT!
他做到了！
- TWELVE HOURS FROM NOW, ANNE,
我的意思是，我们做到了！
I'LL BE AT THE WORLD WATER SLIDING CHAMPIONSHIP,
十二小时后，安妮，
ROCKETING MY WAY TO VICTORY.
我将参加世界水上滑梯锦标赛，
ANKLES LOCKED, ARMS CROSSED,
以火箭般的速度冲向胜利。
ABOUT TO BREAK THE WATERSLIDE SPEED RECORD
脚踝锁定，双臂交叉，
CURRENTLY HELD BY HENRY WONG, AGE NINE.
即将打破目前由九岁的亨利·王保持的水上滑梯速度纪录。
- IS THAT WHY YOU PACKED A MASON JAR OF BACON GREASE?
这就是你打包一罐培根油的原因吗？
SO YOU'LL SLIDE FASTER?
所以你会滑得更快？
- [stammering and shushing]
（结巴和嘘声）
TECHNICALLY, IT'S AGAINST THE RULES. YOU NEVER SAW THIS.
严格来说，这是违反规则的。你从没见过这个。
- THE KID'S NINE, TOM.
那孩子才九岁，汤姆。
- HE'S GREASING TOO, ANNE!
他也在涂油，安妮！
SLIDING USED TO BE PURE, BUT THE GAME'S CHANGED.
滑行曾经是纯粹的，但游戏已经变了。
YOU GOT TO CHANGE WITH IT.
你得跟着变。
LOOK AT THIS KID.
看看这孩子。
HE LOSES NO SPEED IN THE TURNS.
他在转弯时没有减速。
HE'S ONE SLIPPERY SHRIMP. - [gasps]
他真是个滑溜的小虾。
YOU KNOW WHAT I SEE?
你知道我看到了什么吗？
SOMEONE'S DENTED THE CORNER OF OUR NEW TABLET.
有人把我们新平板的角落撞凹了。
- FOCUS ON WHAT'S IMPORTANT.
- 专注于重要的事情。
WE'LL BE ABLE TO BUY ALL THE TABLETS IN THE WORLD
一旦我打破这个纪录，我们就能买下世界上所有的平板。
ONCE I BREAK THIS RECORD. - IS THERE PRIZE MONEY?
- 有奖金吗？
- NO, BUT THERE'S AN OUTLET MALL RIGHT NEXT TO THE PARK.
- 没有，但公园旁边就有一个直销购物中心。
- HAVE YOU SEEN MY SPRAY BRONZER?
- 你看到我的喷雾古铜粉了吗？
- NO, BUT GOOD IDEA.
- 没有，但这是个好主意。
THE BRONZER'LL MASK THE BACON SMELL.
古铜粉能掩盖培根的气味。
NOW YOU'RE THINKING LIKE A GREASER.
现在你开始像个滑头一样思考了。
- IT'S FOR ME.
这是给我的。
IF YOU'RE GONNA TAKE ME TO A WATER PARK,
如果你要带我去水上乐园，
I'D RATHER NOT LOOK LIKE FROSTY THE SNOW MOM.
我宁愿不要看起来像雪人弗罗斯蒂。
- WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
等等，等等，等等，等等。
THIS COULD HELP.
这可能有用。
THE GLARE COMING OFF YOUR PASTY BODY MIGHT DISTRACT HENRY WONG
你那苍白的身体反射的光可能会分散亨利·王的注意力
AND HIS COUSIN.
和他的表兄弟。
THAT'S RIGHT, THERE'S TWO OF THEM, ANNE.
没错，他们有两个，安妮。
- TOM, I CAN'T LET YOU DO THIS.
汤姆，我不能让你这么做。
- NO, NO, NO, NO.
不，不，不，不。
- TWO WONGS DOESN'T MAKE IT RIGHT.
- 两个黄不是对。
- STOP IT!
- 住手！
- HURRY UP! I WANT TO BEAT THE TRAFFIC TO THE WATER PARK. - OKAY, LET ME JUST GET THE COOLER FROM THE FRIDGE.
- 快点！我想避开去水上乐园的交通高峰。 - 好的，让我从冰箱里拿冷却器。
- I'M GONNA WARM UP MY GREASE.
- 我要预热我的油脂。
PARDON ME.
劳驾。
- WHY DO YOU HAVE MY TOWEL? - IT'S NOT YOURS.
- 你为什么拿着我的毛巾？ - 这不是你的。
- OH, YEAH? THEN, UH, WHAT'S THIS?
- 哦，是吗？那，呃，这是什么？
I GUESS LABELING EVERYTHING I OWN
我想给所有我拥有的东西贴标签
DOESN'T MAKE ME SO WEIRD NOW, DOES IT?
现在不显得那么奇怪了，对吧？
- NO, BUT HOLDING YOUR SWIMSUIT UP WITH SUSPENDERS DOES.
- 不，但用吊带挂着你的泳衣确实有点怪。
- THEY'RE SWIM-SPENDERS, AND THEY'RE GONNA CATCH ON.
- 这是游泳背带，它们会流行的。
- COME ON, GUYS, FOCUS.
- 拜托，大家，集中注意力。
EVERYBODY MAKE THEIR BED? all: CHECK.
- 每个人都整理好床铺了吗？
- PICK UP THEIR STUFF OFF THE FLOOR?
- 把地上的东西都捡起来了吗？
all: CHECK.
- 检查。
- BRUSH THEIR TEETH? [all exhaling]
- 刷牙了吗？
COULD HAVE BEEN BETTER.
- 本可以做得更好。
WE DID IT, GUYS. NOTHING'S GONNA STOP US NOW!
- 我们做到了，伙计们。现在没有什么能阻止我们了！
- EVERYBODY STOP, NOW!
- 大家停下，现在！
- SOMEONE LEFT A PRESENT IN THE DOWNSTAIRS TOILET,
- 有人在楼下厕所留下了一份‘礼物’，
AND DIDN'T REMEMBER TO FLUSH.
而且忘了冲水。
WHICH ONE OF YOU WAS IT?
你们谁干的？
all: IT WASN'T ME!
大家：不是我！
- HERE WE GO AGAIN.
- 又来了。
NOBODY DID IT?
没人承认？
- GUYS, COME ON. WHOEVER DID IT, JUST SAY IT.
- 大家，拜托。谁干的，就承认吧。
- BUT I DIDN'T DO IT. - ME NEITHER.
- 但我没干。 - 我也没干。
- HEY, YOU KNOW I LABEL EVERYTHING.
- 嘿，你知道我什么都会标记的。
- THAT'S IT, WE ARE NOT GOING TO THE WATER PARK
- 就这样，我们不去水上乐园了
UNTIL SOMEONE TAKES RESPONSIBILITY.
直到有人承担责任。
all: YOU CAN'T DO THAT! IT'S NOT FAIR.
大家：你不能这样做！这不公平。
- NO, NO, NO, NO.
- 不，不，不，不。
NOBODY IS LEAVING THIS HOUSE UNTIL WE FIND OUT WHO DUNNIT.
在我们找出是谁干的之前，没有人可以离开这房子。
- OR SHOULD WE SAY "POO DUNNIT?"
- 或者我们应该说“便便干的？”
DUN, DUN, DUN!
咚，咚，咚！
- WHY ARE YOU DOING THAT? - IT'S FOR DRAMATIC EFFECT.
- 你为什么要那样做？ - 为了戏剧效果。
DUN, DUN, DUN!
咚，咚，咚！
- QUADDLE UP.
- 快点集合。
THIS IS A QUADMERGENCY.
这是一场紧急的四重危机。
WHOEVER DID IT, JUST CONFESS SO WE CAN GO.
不管是谁干的，快承认吧，这样我们就可以走了。
- IT WASN'T ME.
- 不是我。
- SOMEONE JUST ADMIT BEING THE QUAD WITH THE LOG.
- 有人承认是那个和木头一起的吧。
- YEAH, I WANT TO GO TO THE WATER PARK.
- 是啊，我想去水上乐园。
- ME TOO.
- 我也是。
SO, THIS IS WHAT A QUADDLE'S LIKE, HUH?
- 所以，这就是一起玩的感觉，对吧？
- DAD, GET OUT OF THE QUADDLE.
- 爸爸，你从这上面下来。
- WHAT? HE'S HERE.
- 什么？他在这里。
- BOTH OF YOU GET OUT.
- 你们俩都下来。
- FINE.
- 好吧。
- AND WHY DO YOU SMELL LIKE BACON?
- 还有，你为什么闻起来像培根？
- LET'S JUST SAY I'M IN PEAK SLIDING CONDITION.
- 这么说吧，我正处于最佳滑行状态。
THAT'S ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW.
这就是你需要知道的全部。
- LOOK, I KNOW IT WASN'T ME, WHICH MEANS IT WAS ONE OF YOU.
- 听着，我知道不是我，那就意味着是你们中的一个。
- THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY TO GET TO THE BOTTOM OF THIS.
- 要查清楚这件事只有一个办法。
- WE ALL PROVIDE A SAMPLE AND SEE IF WE HAVE A MATCH?
- 我们每个人都提供一个样本，看看有没有匹配的？
both: NO.
两人: 不行。
- WE GET A SKETCH ARTIST TO DRAW IT AND SEE IF IT LOOKS LIKE ANY OF US?
- 我们找个素描艺术家来画一下，看看像不像我们中的任何一个？
all: NO!
所有人: 不行！
- WE GO IN THERE AND PLAY GOOD PLOP, BAD PLOP, AND TRY TO GET IT TO TALK.
- 我们进去玩“好便便，坏便便”，试着让它说话。
all: NO!
所有人: 不行！
- WE JUST NEED TO INVESTIGATE.
- 我们只需要调查。
GET A GOOD LOOK AT THE EVIDENCE.
- 好好看看这些证据。
TO THE SEAT OF THE CRIME!
- 前往犯罪现场！
- THAT IS NOT MINE.
- 那不是我的。
- IF YOU TURN YOUR HEAD, IT KIND OF LOOKS LIKE A FLAMINGO.
- 如果你转过头，它有点像火烈鸟。
all: OH, YEAH.
大家：哦，是的。
- I SEE IT.
- 我看到了。
THERE'S THE LEG.
- 那里是腿。
- NOW I KIND OF WISH IT WAS MINE.
- 现在我有点希望它是我的。
- IS IT WEIRD WE'RE ALL LOOKING AT THIS RIGHT NOW?
- 我们都在看这个，是不是有点奇怪？
all: YEAH, TOTALLY.
是的，完全正确。
- WE SHOULD STOP.
我们应该停下来。
- STOP RIGHT THERE.
就停在那里。
THIS IS A CRIME SCENE.
这里是犯罪现场。
NOBODY TOUCH ANYTHING.
任何人不得触碰任何东西。
HIDDEN IN THIS ROOM
这个房间里隐藏着
IS EVIDENCE THAT WILL LEAD US TO THE POOPETRATOR,
能引导我们找到罪犯的证据，
AND I'M GONNA FIND IT WITH MY GOOD FRIEND...
而我将和我好朋友一起找到它……
SCIENCE.
科学。
- A MAGNIFYING GLASS?
一个放大镜？
CUTE.
可爱。
A TRUE DETECTIVE RELIES ON ONLY HIS WIT AND KEEN EYE.
真正的侦探只依赖他的智慧和敏锐的眼睛。
YOU DISGUST ME!
你让我恶心！
- WHILE YOU GUYS WASTE OUR TIME WITH SCIENCE AND OBSERVATION,
你们这些人用科学和观察浪费我们的时间，
I'M GONNA SOLVE THIS THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY.
我要用老派的方式解决这个问题。
WE ALL KNOW YOU DID IT, DICKY.
我们都知道是你干的，迪基。
- TAKE IT EASY, YOU KNOW I'M THINNING.
别激动，你知道我在努力。
- ADMIT IT, OR I'LL START PLUCKING.
承认吧，否则我要开始拔毛了。
- IT WASN'T ME!
不是我！
- YES IT WAS,
就是你，
AND I CAN PROVE IT. - OW!
我能证明这一点。 - 哎哟！
- I FOUND THIS HAIR BY THE TOILET,
- 我在马桶旁边发现了这根头发，
AND...
而且...
THE HAIR I JUST PULLED FROM YOUR HEAD IS A PERFECT MATCH.
我刚从你头上拔下来的头发完全吻合。
THIS HAIR IS A CLUE THAT THE POO IS FROM YOU.
这根头发是一个线索，表明那坨便便来自你。
- WHAT'S THAT WEIRD GREEN STUFF ON THE END OF IT?
- 那头发末端那奇怪的绿色东西是什么？
- THAT'S NOTHING, AND THIS HAIR DOESN'T PROVE THAT I DID IT.
- 那没什么，而且这根头发并不能证明是我干的。
IT PROVES THAT RICKY DID IT.
它证明了是Ricky干的。
- WHAT?
- 什么？
- IT'S THE FIRST RULE OF DETECTIVING.
- 这是侦探的第一条规则。
THE FIRST TO POINT THE FINGER IS THE ONE WHO LET IT LINGER.
第一个指手画脚的人，就是罪行停留最久的那个。
- YEAH, THE FIRST TO ISSUE THE CHARGE IS THE ONE
没错，第一个提出指控的人，就是让驳船漂走的那个。
WHO FLOATED THE BARGE.
第一个张口说话的家伙，就是夺走我们水上乐园的那个。
- THE FIRST TO OPEN HIS YAP
唐恩第一个指的别人！
IS THE ONE WHO TOOK THE WATER PARK AWAY FROM US.
没错。
- DAWN POINTED THE FINGER FIRST! - YEAH.
这倒是真的。
- THAT'S TRUE.
别被他的花哨逻辑迷惑了。
- DON'T FALL FOR HIS FANCY LOGIC.
的确是瑞奇干的，
RICKY DID IT,
如果我们追溯他的行踪，就能证明这一点。
AND IF WE RETRACE HIS STEPS, WE CAN PROVE IT.
哎呀呀呀呀，我只是去厕所解决一下个人问题，
- DOH-DEE-DOH-DEE-DOH.
嘟-迪-嘟-迪-嘟。
JUST GOING IN THE POTTY TO DO MY BUSINESS,
只是去厕所办我的事，
AND PLAY MY CROSSWORD PUZZLE GAME.
然后玩我的填字游戏。
WHEE! DON-DEE-DOH-DEE-DOH.
哇！嘟-迪-嘟-迪-嘟。
WHEN HAVE I EVER DOH-DEE-DOH'ED?
我什么时候嘟-迪-嘟过？
- I'M TELLING THE STORY HERE.
我在讲故事呢。
SO, AFTER THE CRIME WAS COMMITTED,
所以，犯罪发生后，
RICKY HAD A LOT ON HIS MIND.
瑞奇心里有很多事。
- GOLLY GEE!
哎呀！
THAT CROSSWORD PUZZLE WAS SO HARD,
那个填字游戏太难了，
I FORGOT TO FLUSH THE TOILET.
我忘了冲马桶。
OH WELL, THEY WON'T BE ABLE TO PIN IT ON ME,
哦，好吧，他们无法将此事归咎于我，
BECAUSE I'M MR. SMARTY-PANTS.
因为我可是聪明绝顶先生。
- BUT THEN, HE AND HIS SMART PANTS PAUSED AT THE DOOR,
- 但随后，他和他的聪明裤子在门口停了下来，
BECAUSE WE ALL KNOW RICKY WON'T TOUCH THE BATHROOM DOORKNOB.
因为我们大家都知道，Ricky是不会碰浴室门把手的。
OH, AND WHAT'S THIS?
哦，这是什么？
A CHIP IN THE TILE, RIGHT WHERE RICKY DROPPED THE TABLET.
瓷砖上的一个缺口，正好是Ricky掉落药片的地方。
- HOW DO YOU KNOW I MADE THAT CHIP?
- 你怎么知道是我弄出的那个缺口？
ANYONE COULD'VE MADE THAT CHIP.
任何人都有可能弄出那个缺口。
YOU CAN'T PROVE ANYTHING WITH THAT CHIP!
你不能仅凭那个缺口证明什么！
- YOU'RE RIGHT, BUT I CAN WITH THIS!
你说得对，但我有这个！
- OH, IT'S ONE OF YOUR LABELS. IT MUST'VE COME OF WHEN
哦，这是你的一张标签。一定是你用衬衫抓住门把手时掉下来的。
YOU GRABBED THE DOORKNOB WITH YOUR SHIRT.
你肯定希望你现在没有给所有东西都贴标签，对吧？
- BET YOU WISH YOU DIDN'T LABEL EVERYTHING NOW, HUH?
你就是肇事者。
- YOU'RE THE POOPETRATOR.
而这份证据会粘住。
- AND THIS EVIDENCE IS GONNA STICK.
终于，谜团解开了！
- FINALLY, MYSTERY SOLVED!
水上乐园，我们来了。
WATER PARK, HERE WE COME.
没那么快！
- NOT SO FAST!
哎哟！
- OW!
虽然证据显示Dicky和Ricky都在犯罪现场，
- ALTHOUGH THE EVIDENCE PLACES BOTH DICKY AND RICKY
虽然证据表明迪基和里基都在犯罪现场，
AT THE SCENE OF THE CRIME,
但毫无疑问，漂浮的火烈鸟属于道恩！
THERE IS NO DOUBT THE FLOATING FLAMINGO BELONGS
道恩，道恩，道恩！
TO DAWN!
我？什么？
- DAWN, DAWN, DAWN!
如果你们中有任何人注意到了，
- ME? WHAT?
你会看到水槽上的这个小橙色污点。
- IF ANY OF YOU HAD BEEN PAYING ATTENTION,
里面有个指纹。
YOU WOULD HAVE NOTICED THIS SMALL ORANGE SMUDGE ON THE SINK.
哦，是吗？
- THERE'S A FINGERPRINT IN IT.
我想知道这是谁的。
- OH, IS THERE?
如果我是个爱赌博的人，我会把一切都押在道恩身上。
I WONDER WHOSE IT IS.
我想知道这是谁的。
IF I WAS A GAMBLING MAN, I'D BET IT ALL ON DAWN.
如果我是个赌徒，我会把所有赌注都押在Dawn身上。
- HOW DO YOU KNOW IT'S MINE?
你怎么知道是我的？
THAT COULD BE ANYBODY'S FINGERPRINT.
那可能是任何人的指纹。
- LOOKS LIKE THE HAND YOU'RE HOLDING IS A ROYAL DIDN'T FLUSH.
看起来你手里的牌像是没洗的皇家同花顺。
- SO I LEFT A FINGERPRINT IN THE BATHROOM,
所以我在浴室留下了指纹，
THAT DOESN'T PROVE ANYTHING.
那并不能证明什么。
- DICKY LEFT A HAIR, RICKY LEFT A NAME TAG,
Dicky留下了一根头发，Ricky留下了一个名牌，
AND NICKY LEFT HIS SPECIAL SPOON IN THE TRASH.
而Nicky把他的特殊勺子留在了垃圾桶里。
- I CAN EXPLAIN.
我可以解释。
FINE!
好吧！
I WAS IN THE BATHROOM LAST NIGHT,
我昨晚确实在洗手间，
BUT SO WERE ALL OF YOU.
但你们所有人也都在。
- HE'S RIGHT.
他说得对。
THERE'S EVIDENCE THAT PLACES US ALL AT THE SCENE OF THE CRIME.
有证据表明我们都曾在犯罪现场。
- ALL RIGHT, WHICH ONE OF YOU
好吧，你们当中谁
IS FINALLY READY TO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY?
终于准备好承担责任了？
all: IT WASN'T ME!
不是我！
- REALLY KIDS?
真的吗，孩子们？
ALL MORNING, AND WE'RE BACK TO WHERE WE STARTED?
整个早上，我们又回到了原点？
THAT'S IT. IF YOU DON'T FIGURE THIS OUT
就这样吧，如果你们在接下来的20分钟内还解决不了这个问题，
IN THE NEXT 20 MINUTES, WE'RE STAYING HOME.
我们就待在家里不去了。
- BUT DON'T WORRY, I WILL BE TEXTING YOU ALL PICTURES
不过别担心，我会给你们发我在打败王家兄弟后庆祝跳舞的照片。
OF ME DOING A CELEBRATORY JIG AFTER I CRUSH THE WONG BOYS.
汤姆，他们不去的话，我们也不去。
- TOM, IF THEY'RE NOT GOING, WE'RE NOT GOING.
真的吗？
- SERIOUSLY?
你本来就不太想去公园。
YOU NEVER WANTED TO GO TO THE PARK.
你根本就不想让我赢。你更关心的是你那宝贵的晒黑肤色，而不是你宝贵的汤姆。
YOU NEVER WANTED ME TO WIN. YOU WERE MORE CONCERNED
好吧，自私的鬼魂卡斯帕，
WITH YOUR PRECIOUS TAN THAN YOUR PRECIOUS TOM.
也许是你留下的那个数字二，
WELL, CASPER THE SELFISH GHOST,
就是为了不让我成为第一。
MAYBE YOU'RE THE ONE WHO LEFT THE NUMBER TWO,
也许是你留下了第二名，
JUST SO I COULDN'T BE NUMBER ONE.
只是为了让我不能成为第一名。
- ME?
- 我？
MAYBE YOU LEFT THE UNCLAIMED PACKAGE IN THE P.U. BOX.
也许是你把未领取的包裹放在了P.U.信箱里。
MAYBE YOU WANTED TO GO BY YOURSELF
也许你想要独自去，
SO YOUR KIDS WOULDN'T DISTRACT YOU FROM YOUR ULTIMATE GOAL.
这样你的孩子们就不会分散你达成终极目标的注意力。
BEING FASTER THAN A NINE YEAR-OLD BOY.
比一个九岁男孩跑得更快。
- AND HIS COUSIN!
- 还有他的表兄弟！
- OKAY, LOOK. THE ONLY THING
- 好吧，看这里。我们唯一确定的是，
WE KNOW FOR SURE IS THAT SOMEONE IN THIS ROOM DID IT.
这个房间里的某个人做了这件事。
- BUT WHO? WAS IT DICKY?
但是谁？是Dicky吗？
RICKY?
Ricky？
DAWN?
Dawn？
OR NICKY?
还是Nicky？
OR COULD IT BE ANNE?
或者是Anne？
- AREN'T YOU FORGETTING SOMEONE?
你是不是忘了谁？
- RIGHT.
对。
MAYBE IT WAS THE DOG?
也许是狗？
- OR MAYBE IT WAS TOM?
或者也许是Tom？
YOU'RE RIGHT, IT DOES ADD DRAMA.
你说得对，这确实增加了戏剧性。
- ALL RIGHT, HARPERS,
好吧，哈珀家的孩子们，
IF WE WANT TO GO TO THE WATER PARK TODAY,
如果我们今天想去水上乐园，
THE FORGETFUL FLUSHER NEEDS TO FESS UP.
那个健忘的冲厕所的人需要坦白。
- MOM'S RIGHT, IT'S TIME TO SHOW THE POOP, THE WHOLE POOP,
妈妈说得对，是时候展示便便，全部的便便，
AND NOTHING BUT THE POOP.
除了便便什么都不展示。
- FINE.
好吧。
MOM, DAD,
妈妈，爸爸，
YOU KNOW HOW YOU WANT US TO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY FOR STUFF?
你们知道你们希望我们对自己的行为负责吗？
WELL, HERE IT GOES.
那么，我要说了。
I ADMIT IT. all: AHH!
我承认。
- I WENT INTO THE BATHROOM LAST NIGHT,
昨晚我进了浴室，
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT ANYBODY TO KNOW
因为我不想让任何人知道
I WAS SNEAKING SOME OF DAD'S MAGIC HAIR-GROWING SMOOTHIE,
我在偷爸爸的神奇生发奶昔，
BECAUSE I WAS ALL FREAKED OUT ABOUT MY THINNING HAIR.
因为我对自己的稀疏头发感到非常恐慌。
THAT'S WHY THERE'S GREEN STUFF ON THE HAIR YOU FOUND.
这就是为什么你们找到的头发上有绿色的东西。
SORRY DAD.
对不起，爸爸。
- DICKY, YOU KNOW THERE'S A LOT OF MILK IN THAT SMOOTHIE. - AND YOU'RE LACTOSE INTOLERANT.
迪基，你知道那奶昔里有很多牛奶。
- EXACTLY, WHICH MEANS YOU CAN'T PIN THE POOP ON ME,
而你对乳糖不耐受。
BECAUSE IF I'D DONE IT, THERE'D BE NO SOLID EVIDENCE.
没错，这意味着你不能把拉肚子的事怪在我头上，
all: EWW!
因为如果是我干的，就不会有任何固体证据。
- "EWW" ALL YOU WANT.
尽管你们说'EWW'吧。
I'M INNOCENT, SO IT'S DEFINITELY ONE OF YOU.
我是无辜的，所以肯定是你中的一个。
- FINE, I GUESS IT'S TIME FOR ME TO CONFESS.
好吧，我想是时候我该坦白了。
all: OH!
哦！
- I WENT INTO THE BATHROOM LAST NIGHT
我昨晚进了洗手间
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT ANYONE
因为我不想让任何人
TO KNOW THAT I'M TERRIFIED TO RIDE THE RED BOMBER.
知道我害怕乘坐红色轰炸机。
SO, I WAS WATCHING VIDEOS OF PEOPLE RIDING IT
所以，我正在看人们乘坐它的视频
TO PROVE TO MYSELF IT'S NOT REALLY THAT SCARY.
来向自己证明
BUT THAT THING IS SCARY!
它其实并没有那么可怕。
AND THAT'S HOW I CHIPPED THE TILE,
这就是我如何弄碎了瓷砖，
AND DENTED YOUR TABLET.
还弄凹了你的平板。
SORRY. - IT'S OKAY.
对不起。 - 没关系。
- AHA!
- 啊哈！
SO YOU TOOK THE POOP AND FLEW THE COOP!
所以你拉完屎就溜了！
- NO, I COULDN'T HAVE.
- 不，我不可能那样做。
BECAUSE WHEN I GET SCARED, NO TRAINS LEAVE THE STATION.
因为当我害怕时，火车是不会离站的。
- WHAT? - MY FLUME GETS LOG-JAMMED.
- 什么？ - 我的滑道会堵塞。
- HUH?
- 嗯？
- I CAN'T MAKE A DOODIE!
- 我拉不出来！
all: EWW!
哎呀！
- "EWW ALL" YOU WANT.
- 你们都想'哎呀'。
I'M INNOCENT.
我是无辜的。
- SO, IT'S ONE OF YOU TWO.
- 那么，是你们两个中的一个。
- OR YOU AND MOM.
- 或者是你和妈妈。
- RIGHT, OR MOM.
- 对，或者是妈妈。
- FINE, I CONFESS.
- 好吧，我坦白。
I DID IT.
是我干的。
all: [gasping]
大家：[倒吸一口气]
- I ATE MOM'S ICE CREAM.
- 我吃了妈妈的冰淇淋。
I TRIED TO RESIST,
我曾试图抗拒，
BUT THE GREEN GLOW WAS LIKE A SIREN'S CALL.
但那绿色的光芒犹如塞壬的召唤。
BUT THEN, I GOT SOME UNEXPECTED CANINE COMPANY.
然而，我得到了一些意想不到的犬伴。
- [woof]
汪
AFTER I SHOOED HIM OUT, I KNEW I HAD TO THROW AWAY THE EVIDENCE.
在我赶走他之后，我知道我必须销毁证据。
all: EWW!
哎呀！
- "EWW" ALL YOU WANT.
你们尽管‘哎呀’吧。
ME EATING THE ICE CREAM PROVES I DIDN'T FILL THE BOWL
我吃了冰淇淋，这证明我没有装满碗
AND TAKE A STROLL.
然后去散步。
- HE'S RIGHT.
他说得对。
THAT ICE CREAM GLOWS NO MATTER WHAT BOWL IT'S IN.
不论放在哪个碗里，这冰淇淋都会发光。
- SORRY, MOM. - IT'S OKAY.
- 对不起，妈妈。- 没关系。
- WELL, IF IT WASN'T RICKY, DICKY, OR NICKY,
- 好吧，如果不是瑞奇、迪基或尼克做的，
THAT BRINGS US TO DAWN, DAWN, DAWN!
- 那就只剩下唐了，唐，唐！
- FINE!
- 好吧！
I'M TIRED OF LYING.
我厌倦了撒谎。
IT'S TIME I TOLD THE TRUTH.
是时候说出真相了。
all: AHH!
啊哈！
- I WAITED TILL EVERYONE WAS ASLEEP,
- 我等到大家都睡着了，
THEN I TIPTOED OVER TO THE TOILET, AND...
然后悄悄走到厕所，然后...
TOOK OUT MOM'S SPRAY BRONZER,
拿出了妈妈的喷雾古铜色化妆品，
WHICH I HAD STASHED EARLIER.
这是我之前藏起来的。
I WANTED TO BE TAN FOR OUR RED BOMBER PICTURE.
我想在拍红色轰炸机照片时看起来晒黑一些。
- WHAT? THAT STUFF'S NOT FOR KIDS!
什么？那东西不适合小孩用！
PLUS, IT'S MESSY, AND IT DOESN'T DRY FOR HOURS.
而且，它很乱，要好几个小时才能干。
- EXACTLY!
没错！
I TESTED IT ON THE BACK OF MY LEGS,
我在腿后面试了试，
SO IF I HAD BEEN THE ONE TO SIT ON THE TOILET,
所以如果是我坐在这个马桶上，
THE SEAT WOULD BE ORANGE,
马桶座会变成橙色，
WHICH MEANS IT WAS NOT ME WHO SET THE FLAMINGO FREE.
这意味着不是我放走了火烈鸟。
- WELL, IF IT WASN'T ANY OF US, THEN IT HAD TO BE...
- 好吧，如果不是我们中的任何一个，那么就只能是……
- WHEN WAS YOUR LAST BIG MEAL?
- 你上次大餐是什么时候？
- WHERE WERE YOU BETWEEN THE HOURS OF MIDNIGHT AND 6:00?
- 午夜到早上6点之间你在哪里？
- YOU GOT AN ALIBI?
- 你有不在场证明吗？
- GUYS, LOOK, THE ONLY THING WE KNOW FOR SURE IS YA BUSTED.
- 伙计们，看，我们唯一确定的是你被抓包了。
- WHAT ARE YOU KIDS TALKING ABOUT?
- 你们这些孩子在说什么？
- IT'S PRETTY CLEAR THEY KNOW YOU DID IT, ANNE.
- 很明显他们知道是你干的，安妮。
SORRY, BUT YA BUSTED.
抱歉，但你被抓包了。
- AH, IF ANYBODY'S BUSTED, IT'S YA.
- 啊，如果有谁被抓包了，那就是你。
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- 你在说什么？
[all talking at once]
大家都在同时说话
[barking]
狗在叫
- OH, GO AHEAD. APOLOGIES.
哦，继续。道歉。
ALL RIGHT. GO ON.
好吧。继续。
[splash]
溅水声
- DID HE JUST--
他刚刚是...？
- AND DID HE FORGET TO--
他是不是忘了...？
[toilet flushes]
马桶冲水声
- HUH.
嗯。
IT WAS THE DOG. I WAS RIGHT.
是那只狗。我猜对了。
I GUESS ALL THAT TRAINING PAID OFF.
我想所有的训练都值了。
- YOU TRAINED THE DOG TO DO THAT?
- 你训练狗做那件事？
- WELL, WE TALKED ABOUT IT,
- 嗯，我们讨论过，
BUT I DIDN'T THINK HE WAS LISTENING.
但我没想到他在听。
- WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
- 你知道什么？
THAT'S ONE MYSTERY NONE OF US GOT RIGHT.
那是一个我们都没猜对的谜。
- BUT IT'S NO MYSTERY WHO'S ABOUT TO GET WONG.
- 但谁要倒霉了，这已经不是谜了。
all: TO THE WATER PARK!
大家：去水上乐园！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
[whistling melody]
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ ♪
- [cheerful melody]
- ♪
♪